# Shanna McKee

630.835.9059 | shannamckee2011@gmail.com | LinkedIn

### **Professional Summary**

Accomplished and high performing Director executive with demonstrated ability to use data analytics, business intelligence, predictive analytics, and data visualizations to help businesses improve leadership, strategic planning, and accompanying results. Background in leadership, curriculum development, higher education, increasing profits, reducing costs, and transforming success standards. Experienced in leading and supervising operational and leadership teams. Strong ability to frame and break down complex business problems and recommend targeted, practical solutions. Highly skilled in creating, delivering effective presentations of complex topics to audiences of all shapes and knowledge. Strategic-thinking individual experienced in turning low-performing organizations into top revenue producers. Offering engaging and pleasant personality with expertise improving customer relationships and building strategic partnerships. Highly committed, positive management style, a true leader, mentor, inspires confidence in others, and empower team members. Embraces continuous learning and improvement.

#### **Skills & Abilities**

- TEAM LEADERSHIP
- TIME MANAGEMENT
- ONLINE INSTRUCTION
- LEADERSHIP & STRATEGY DEVELOPMENT
- ADVANCED DATA ANALYTICS
- HIGHER EDUCATION
- PRODUCT STRATEGY
- MARKETING STRATEGY
- PRODUCT / STRATEGIC PLANNING
- LABOR MARKET RESEARCH
- PROGRAM MANAGEMENT
- PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT

- BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE
- BUSINESS STRATEGY
- RESOURCE PLANNING
- DATA VISUALIZATION
- CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT / ASSESSMENT
- EXCEL / TABLEAU
- PYTHON / SQL / AWS
- BUSINESS ANALYSIS
- PRESENTATIONS & STORYTELLING
- TALENT ACQUISITION
- STRATEGIC COMMUNICATION
- MENTOR / STUDENT ADVOCATE

# Experience

#### FOUNDER & CEO | MCKEE THEORY INC. | MAY 2021 - PRESENT

- · Negotiate terms of business acquisitions to increase business base and solidify market presence.
- · Create and identify opportunities to increase profit, traction, and efficiency.
- · Cultivate forward-thinking, inclusive and performance-driven company culture to lead industry innovations.
- Establish, optimized and enforced business policies to maintain consistency across industry operations.
- · Define company roles and responsibilities to establish and enhance processes.
- · Form senior leadership team through rigorous interviews and extensive candidate research.
- · Identify business development challenges and customer concerns for proactive resolution.
- · customer concerns for proactive resolution.
- · Improve current data infrastructures, create, and track metrics

- Improve performance management system and introduce data analytics program to develop future leaders.
- · Interview, supervise, and motivate staff members to achieve optimal productivity.
- · Lead recruitment and development of strategic alliances to maximize utilization of existing talent and capabilities.

#### DIRECTOR OF ACADEMICS, DATA ANALYTICS | FULLSTACK | JUNE 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022

- Managed and elevated a best-in-class immersive data analytics education program for smart, ambitious students from all walks of life.
- · Recruited, onboarded entire data analytics instructional team.
- · Built a collaborative, positive, team environment offering innovation, empowerment, and support.
- · Responsible for driving departmental culture, promoting data-driven decision making, marketing, and investment planning.
- · Responsible for driving departmental culture, promoting data-driven decision making, marketing, and investment planning.
- · Evaluated company documentation to verify alignment with regulatory requirements.
- · Formed strategic partnerships and connected with potential clients to drive business development.
- Delivered experience to students that is superlative, creates ambassadors, and elicits exceptional reviews and buzz.
- · Proven ability to create change across organization, working with IT teams to define architectures.
- Lead teams through data story using analytics data strategy developing and driving analytics data strategy, including data captures, data enhancements, data cleansing, and data models.
- · Spearheaded innovative approaches to resource allocation and strategic planning.
- · Worked closely with organizational leadership and board of directors to guide operational strategy.
- Experience leading teams developing big data analytics platforms and solutions.
- Collaborated with management and fellow supervisors to organize operations and achieve demanding schedule targets.
- · Analyzed business needs while soliciting customer feedback for process improvements.
- · Oversaw operations and provided corrective feedback to achieve daily and long-term goals.

# SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT | MCKEE THEORY INC POWERED BY FULLSTACK | JANUARY 2021 – JUNE 2021

- · Created data analytics program from ground up.
- · Developed and supported analytical technologies to give partner solid, program content.
- · Developed program framework for both part-time and full-time programs.
- · Developed content curriculum for Excel, Presentations, SQL, Python, Tableau, and AWS
- · Recorded lesson video replays and student facing resources.
- · Designed and prepared instructional materials, resources, lesson plans, and training.
- Facilitated product development with implementation of standard best practices.
- · Created recruiting and onboarding documents for instructional team talent acquisition.
- · Communicated and collaborated across departments to identify and prioritize developmental concepts.
- · Assembled, installed and tested new equipment and trained users in effective operation.
- Effectively implemented best training practices and adult learning principles in planning and creation of instructional materials.

- · Worked closely with instructors to prepare online materials, content, and tools to facilitate training globally.
- · Performed technical interviews and evaluated live demo lessons, while offering feedback on ideal candidates while building instructional teams for upcoming cohorts.

#### DATA ANALYTICS EDUCATOR | THINKFUL | FEBRUARY 2020 - JANURARY 2021

- Supported students by acting as advisor, counselor, and support system as completed courses and land their first industry job.
- Meet with students 1-on-1 in online video sessions to provide technical and professional support as student progresses through curriculum.
- Built and utilized reporting systems to keep customers and management in loop with latest information.
- Conducted 1-on-1 mock interviews and assessments via video calls and provide written feedback to students based on assessment rubrics.
- · Hosted online video sessions on topics of expertise (in alignment with curriculum offerings) for groups of students seeking live support between mentor sessions.
- Provided in-demand support to technical questions and guidance requests that come to Technical Coaching team through text and video in timely manner.
- · Partnered with project team members to identify and quickly address problems.
- · Identified innovative and automated approaches to routine tasks, making suggestions that were widely received.
- · Collaborated with project owners and team members to set ambitious but achievable goals
- Planned and arranged meetings with external organizations and individuals, enabling parties to meet and discuss project progress.
- · Developed content curriculum for Excel, Presentations, SQL, Python, Tableau, and AWS
- · Recorded lesson video replays and student facing resources.
- · Designed and prepared instructional materials, resources, lesson plans, and training.

#### RESEARCH ANALYST | ELGIN COMMUNITY COLLEGE | OCTOBER 2013 - JANURARY 2018

- · Analyzed statistical data using both modern and traditional methods.
- Gathered, arranged and corrected research data to create representative graphs and charts highlighting results for presentations.
- · Tracked key metrics and developed spreadsheets and data models.
- · Supported and developed data requests and research findings across departments institutionally.
- Conducted comparative studies of student demographic/success trends, while creating and revising enrollment projection models.
- · Lead enrollment evaluation across institution Developed in-house processes and applications that effectively report to ICCB, VFA, IPEDS, and statewide survey tool.
- Mentored and guided executive team during business development decision-making to optimize profitability, marketing strategy and communications planning.
- Informed supervisors and company leaders on markets and regional sales needs to best meet student needs and maximize departmental revenue.
- · Supported and developed data requests and research findings across departments institutionally.

- Examined previously used data elements to create new initiatives, such as accelerated learning programs.
- · Studied demographic data to determine optimal targets, competitor offerings and tactics for persuasion.

# **Education**

# POST MASTERS CERTIFICATION | 2017 | CAPELLA UNIVERSITY

· Major: Leadership in Higher Education

#### MASTERS OF SCIENCE | 2014 | CAPELLA UNIVERSITY

· Major: Evaluation, Research, and Measurement

#### BACHELOR OF ARTS | 2006 | NORTHERN ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY

· Major: Psychology